waterfox.net 2019-12-09

# Privacy Policy | Waterfox Web Browser

## Privacy Policy

Waterfox Browser & Website Privacy Policy

### March 14, 2018

Your privacy is an important factor that Waterfox (that's us) considers in the development of each of our products and services. We are committed to being transparent and open. This Waterfox Privacy Policy explains generally how we receive information about you, and what we do with that information once we have it. You can also read our product privacy notices and FAQs to get more detail with respect to each of our products and services.

## What do we mean by "personal information?"

For us, "personal information" means information which identifies you, like your name or email address.

Any information that falls outside of this is "non-personal information."

If we store your personal information with information that is non-personal, we will consider the combination as personal information. If we remove all personal information from a set of data then the remaining is non-personal information.

## How do we learn information about you?

We learn information about you when: 

  * you give it to us directly (e.g., when you choose to send us crash reports);

## What do we do with your information once we have it?

When you give us information, we will use it in the ways for which you've given us permission. Generally, we use your information to help us provide and improve our products and services for you.

## When do we share your information with others?

Even though we don't collect any such information, just in-case: 

  * If our organizational structure or status changes (if we undergo a restructuring, are acquired, or go bankrupt) we may pass your information to a successor.

## What if we change this privacy policy or any of our privacy notices?

We may need to change this policy and our notices. The updates will be posted online. If the changes are substantive, we will announce the update through Waterfox's usual channels for such announcements such as blog posts and forums. Your continued use of the product or service after the effective date of such changes constitutes your acceptance of such changes. To make your review more convenient, we will post an effective date at the top of the page.

### March 14, 2018

We care about your privacy. When Waterfox (that's us) collects information about you, our Waterfox Privacy Policy describes how we handle that information.

This privacy notice applies to Waterfox operated websites and mobile apps, which include the domains waterfoxproject.org, waterfox.net.

Things you should know: 

  * Social Media: If you engage with our social media accounts, such as Twitter and Facebook, we may receive personal information about you. If you use these networks, their privacy policies apply, and you are encouraged to read them.

We may use cookies, third party web analytics, device information, and IP addresses for functionality and to better understand user interaction with our products, services, and communications. 

  * Functionality: We may use cookies, device information and IP addresses to enhance functionality of certain products, services, and communications. For example: 
    * Cookies are used to remember your Waterfox language preference and Waterfox add-ons. They also assist with user sign-in and authentication so you can bypass entering your passwords on certain Waterfox websites.
    * IP addresses are used to customize communications by language and country.
  * Metrics: We may also use cookies, device information and IP addresses, cookies and third party services to help us understand in the aggregate how users engage with our products, services, communications, websites, online campaigns, snippets, devices, and other platforms. We use: 
    * Google Analytics, which places a cookie on your device, to obtain metrics on how users engage with our websites. This helps us to improve site content.

You can control individual cookie preferences, indicate your cookie preferences to others, and opt-out of web analytics and optimization tools. 

  * Cookie History: You can accept or decline individual cookies in your Waterfox preferences in the Tools/Options/Privacy history section. Note that certain features of our products and services may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
  * Do Not Track: Waterfox does not track users across third party websites to provide targeted advertising. If you have configured your browser to send a “Do Not Track” signal when accessing our websites, Waterfox will not utilize any of the tools described in the Metrics section.
  * Analytics & Optimization: Follow the instructions below to prevent data collection about your visits to Waterfox websites: 
    * Google: Install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on, which keeps your visits anonymous and prohibits data transmission to Google Analytics. Some waterfox.net pages use clear GIFs which communicate with DoubleClick to understand the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns; you can control personalized ads from DoubleClick in Google's ad settings (you will be prompted to sign-into your Google Account).
  * Social Media: The social sharing buttons on Waterfox websites are designed not to share data with the social media provider until you specifically click the button.

Some Waterfox websites allow you to make a donation. These transactions are processed by third parties, and not Waterfox. 

  * Payment Processing: Waterfox does not receive any financial information, which is transmitted from you to our third party vendors for processing. The name of the third party will be displayed at the time of the transaction.
